April 20th through deep water Horizon drilling rig
About 40 miles off the coast of Louisiana
11 workers lost their life
17 others were injured
And soon nearly a mile beneath the surface of the ocean
Oil began spewing into the water
Already this oil spill is the worst environmental disaster America has ever faced
And I'm like an earthquake or hurricane
It's not a single event that doesn't damage in a matter of minutes for days
The millions of gallons of oil spilled into the Gulf of Mexico an epidemic
One that we will be fighting for months
And even years
But make no mistake
We will fight this
Spell with everything we've got for as long as it takes
We will make BP pay for the damage their company has caught
And we will do whatever is necessary
To help the Gulf Coast and its people recover from this tragedy
We have known the days of cheap and easily accessible oil or number
We talked and talked about the need to an American Century long addiction to fossil fuel
And for decades we have failed to act with a sense of urgency that this challenge requires
Time and again
The path forward has been blocked
Not only oil industry lobbyist but also by a lack of political courage
And Camera
The consequences of our inaction or Not In Plain Sight
Countries like China or investing in clean energy jobs in America
Each day we spend nearly 1 billion dollars of our wealth to foreign countries
For there or
Today is we look to the Gulf
We see an entire way of life being threatened by a medicine cloud of
Black fruit
We cannot consign our children to this future
The tragedy unfolding on our Coast
Is the most painful and Powerful reminder yet that the time to embrace
Now is the moment for this generation National mission
To unleash America's Innovation and seize control of our own destiny
Each of us has a part to play in a new future that will benefit all of us
We recover from this recession
The transition to clean energy has the potential to grow our economy and create millions of jobs
But only if we accelerate that Transit
Only if we seize the moment
And only if we rally together and act as one nation
Workers and entrepreneurs scientist
And citizens
The public and private sectors
Approach I will not accept
Is an action
Sure I will not settle for is the idea that this challenged is somehow too big and too difficult to me
You know the same thing was said about our ability to produce enough planes and tanks in World War II
The same thing was said about our ability to harness the Science and Technology
And yet time and again
We have refused to settle for the paltry limits of conventional wisdom
Instead what has defined it as a nation since our founding is the capacity
Our determination to fight for the America we were children
The oil spill
Is not the last crisis America will face
This nation is known hard times before and we will surely know them again
What season through
What has always seen us through
Is our strength
How resilience
And our unyielding faith that something better awaits us
If we summon the courage to reach for it