Change your posture
For 2 minutes
Before I give it away
I want to ask you to right now do a little audit of your body and what you're doing with your body
So how many viewers making yourself
Smaller major hunching
Can your legs may be wrapping your ankle sometimes we hold on to our arms like this
Sometimes we are spread out
ICU
I want you to pay attention to that in a few minutes
It could significantly
So we're really fast
And we're particularly interested
In other people's body
You're interested in
An awkward interaction or a smile or contemptuous
Lancer naevia a very awkward wink
Or maybe even something like a handshake
Policeman gets to shake hands with the president
United
Who becomes the prime minister